# Edgar Fernandez

San Diego, CA 92108 <u>Edgar.Fernand@outlook.com</u> (360) 932-6524

## **Summary Statement**

A service driven individual with over 4 years providing support to customers in a team-based environment, with 2 years working data entry in a medical laboratory setting. I am looking for a position that can utilize my knowledge and gain experience in the IT field as a junior frontend developer.

## **Skills and Qualification**

Punctual

. Detail-oriented

. Data Entry

Time-Management

# **Work Experience**

### Sharp Healthcare, San Diego, California

May 2021- Present

Lab Assistant

- Assist with the pre-analytical, analytical, and post-analytical lab processes.
- Communicate effectively with nurses and different departments of the lab in regard to laboratory orders.
- Performs data entry and specimen processing; organize and process orders; checks working material inventory with minimal supervision.

#### Quest Diagnostics, Seattle, Washington

**June 2019 – April 2021** 

Specimen Technician I/Pre-Analytic Assistant I

- Employee of the Month, Awarded for Positive Attitude and Dedication, January 2020
- Maintained productivity for Specimen Processing with 300+ test processed per day and continuously exceeded Tech Ops. defer metric of 150+ aliquots per hour.
- Was responsible for overseeing closing Tech Ops' department with a team of three associates.
- Complete all assigned data entry assignments within required timeframe while maintaining a high level of accuracy.
- Able to use laboratory equipment such as centrifuge, bulk sorter, and decapper while
  adhering to proper procedures for handling biohazardous materials, chemical handling
  procedures, lab safety protocols, and lab cleanliness guidelines.
- Prepare specimens for designated departments, testing, and excess for storage.

# Ross Dress for Less, Seattle, Washington

**December 2014- June 2018** 

Night Stock Associate, 2018 - 2019

- . Employee of the Month in November 2018
- Responsible for preparing efficient workflow by setting up workstations and equipment used for processing stocks.
- Trained new associates on efficient processing procedures according to company guidelines.
- Process and stock 4500+ units with high accuracy, exceeding company expectation for productivity and speed per night.

## Ross Dress for Less, Seattle, Washington

Sales Associate, 2014-2018

- Employee of the Month in June 2017
- Train new associates on cash office, markdown, cashier, and general sales floor maintenance.
- Routinely helped as many as 100+ customers in the sales floor each day, while balancing the needs of multiple customers simultaneously in a fast-paced retail outlet.
- Process an average of 300+ transactions in registers, while maintaining the company's speed and accuracy expectations.
- In the cash office: responsible for balancing 28 cash registers and the safe daily; prepare daily cash/check deposits and ordering change as needed; keeping records of daily/monthly voided transactions, sales, and till balancing summaries.
- Functioned as Cashier, Fitting Room Associate, Cash Office Associate, Trainer, Markdown Lead, MOD Plus.

#### **Education and Awards**

#### Coding Boot Camp at UC San Diego Extension, September 2021- May 2021

A 24- week course, from the University of California San Diego, that teaches web development skills such as HTLM, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Express, MySQL databases, NoSQL Database and React,js.

Associate of Arts Degree, 2019, Seattle Central College, Seattle, WA

#### President's Volunteer Service Award, 2013

Presented by the Corporation for National and Community Service to recognize and appreciate the commitment made through my volunteer services.